"Southwest Remembered: A Story of Urban Renewal" Oral History Project OHP011
People's Archive, MLK Library
"Southwest Remembered: A Story of Urban Renewal" Oral History Project
1983-1985
People's Archive, MLK Library
Smith, Dolores
OHP011
2.5 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
Dolores Smith is a photographer and filmmaker located in Washington, D.C. When she conducted the oral history interviews for this project she was a news photographer at WJLA-TV.
Custodial History
Dolores Smith conducted these interviews between 1983 and 1985, which were a part of her film project Southwest Remembered. The film project was funded by a grant from the D.C. Humanities Council. Following production of the film the tapes and transcripts were donated to the Library in the early 1990s. There is no deed of gift for this collection, but all interviewee releases are granted to the Library.
Scope and Contents
Between 1983 and 1985, Dolores Smith conducted 33 oral history interviews as a part of her film project "Southwest Remembered: A Story of Urban Renewal." Interviewees were residents, business owners, and others with longstanding connections to the Southwest neighborhood. Topics include the Southwest neighborhood before urban renewal, the effects of urban renewal on the neighborhood and community, childhood and life experiences, and work and social life.
Oral History; Southwest (Washington, D.C.); Neighborhoods; Urban renewal
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews except 11-21.
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings except 11-02, 11-16, 11-17, 11-19, 11-20, 11-24 and 11-26.
  - James Banks, 1984 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lucretia Blackstone, 1983 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Barbara Brannon, 1984 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clara Brewer, 1985 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Walter Butler, 1983 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mignon Coates, 1983 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Morris Engle, 1985 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Michael Graham, 1983 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Norman Haddad, 1983 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Margaret Headley, 1985 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mary Jefferson, 1983 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clyde Jones, 1983 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - John Lucas, 1983 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Jessie Lancaster, 1983 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clifton Meade, 1983 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Harry Olmstead, 1984 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Anna Miller, 1985 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Laura Petaway and Pearl Thomas, 1983 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Henry Reuss, 1984 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - George Riseling, 1984 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Janette and Edna Rosenberg, 1984 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mary Schneider and Young Duk, 1983 March (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Betty Shapiro, 1983 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stan Sherman, 1984 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Daniel Thurz, 1984 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Steve Wiggins, 1983 June 11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Interviews
  - James Banks, 1984 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 11-01)
  - Barbara Brannon, 1984 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 11-03)
  - Clara Brewer, 1985 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 11-04)
  - Clara Brewer, 1985 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 11-04)
  - Walter Butler, 1983 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 11-05)
  - Walter Butler, 1983 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 11-05)
  - Mignon Coates, 1983 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 11-06)
  - Morris Engle, 1985 April 14 (Box 3, Folder 11-07)
  - Michael Graham, 1983 February 17 (Box 3, Folder 11-08)
  - Norman Haddad, 1983 February 24 (Box 3, Folder 11-09)
  - Margaret Headley, 1985 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 11-10)
  - Mary Jefferson, 1983 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 11-11)
  - Mary Jefferson, 1983 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 11-11)
  - Clyde Jones and Mr and Mrs. Mallory, 1983 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Clyde Jones and Mr and Mrs. Mallory, 1983 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - John Lucas, 1983 March 19 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Jessie Lancaster, 1983 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
  - Jessie Lancaster, 1983 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
  - Clifton Meade, 1983 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 11-15)
  - Clifton Meade, 1983 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 11-15)
  - Laura Petaway and Pearl Thomas, 1983 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 11-18)
  - Laura Petaway and Pearl Thomas, 1983 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 11-18)
  - Samuel Rosenberg (Box 3, Folder 11-21)
  - Janette and Edna Rosenberg, 1984 March 9 (Box 3, Folder 11-22)
  - Mary Schneider and Young Duk, 1983 March (Box 3, Folder 11-23)
  - Stan Sherman, 1984 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 11-25)
  - Steve Wiggins, 1983 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 11-27)
  - Steve Wiggins, 1983 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 11-27)